<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="js7_job_documentation_v1.1.xsl"?>
<description xmlns="http://www.sos-berlin.com/schema/js7_job_documentation_v1.1"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.sos-berlin.com/schema/js7_job_documentation_v1.1 http://www.sos-berlin.com/schema/js7_job_documentation_v1.1.xsd">

    <job name  = "MonitoringJob"
         title = " Checks the status of the Controller, Agents and JOC Cockpit"
         category="Monitoring;JITL">
        <script language   = "java"
                java_class = "com.sos.jitl.jobs.monitoring.MonitoringJob"
                resource   = "1"/>
    </job>

    <configuration>
 
        <params id="job_parameter">
            <param name="controller_id" required="false">
                <note>
                	<title>The Controller ID indicates the Controller that has to be checked.</title>
                	<p>
						Optionally specifies the identification of the Controller to be checked. By default the current Controller is used.			
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>

            <param name="monitor_report_dir" required="true">
                <note>
                	<title>The directory where the check result is stored</title>
                	<p>
Specifies the directory to which the job will store health status report files (.json). The directory has to exist prior to running the job and has to be in reach of the Agent that runs the job. 

<ul>
<li>An absolute or relative path can be specified.</li>
<li>An expression can be used., for example  env('JS7_AGENT_DATA') ++ '/monitor'</li>
</ul>                     
					</p>
                  
                </note>
            </param>                     

            <param name="monitor_report_max_files" required="one of workflow or job" data_type="integer">
                <note>
                    <title>Limit for the maximum number of files in &lt;monitor_report_dir&gt; </title>
                   <p>
The number of report files created will be limited to this value. Older report files will be removed when this value is exceeded                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
                     
                <param name="from" required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>Parameter &lt;from&gt; for the email job</title>
                    <p>
Specifies the e-mail address that is used to send mail for notices and alerts. The argument is used by the job to create the subject and body return variables.
					</p>
                </note>
                         
            </param>
      
             
        </params>
                
        <params id="return_parameter">
            
            <param name="monitor_report_date" required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>The monitor report date</title>
                    <p>
The date and time for which the health status check has been performed. The date format is yyyy-MM-dd.HH-mm-ss.K, for example 2022-07-31.23-12-59.Z indicating UTC time                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param name="monitor_report_file" required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>The name of the result file</title>
                    <p>
The path to the report file created for the health status check.	                    
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param name="subject" required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>The subject for the result email</title>
                    <p>
                        Returns the subject for the result email.
                        <ul>
                        <li>JS7 Monitor: Notice from: &lt;mailSmtpFrom&gt; at: &lt;monitorReportDate&gt;</li>
                        <li>JS7 Monitor: Alert from: &lt;mailSmtpFrom&gt; at: &lt;monitorReportDate&gt;</li>
                        </ul>
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param name="body" required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>The body for the result email</title>
                    <p>
The body of an e-mail for use with a later MailJob, by default the value is the same as for the subject.
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>             
            <param name="result" required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>Whether the check returns healthy or not healthy</title>
                    <p>
The number of problems identified during the health status check. A value 0 indicates absence of problems, other values indicate existence of problems.	
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
             
            

        </params>

    </configuration>

    <documentation>
    
        <note>
            <title>What is the purpose of this job?</title>
            <p>
The JITL MonitoringJob template can be used to perform health checks of JS7 JOC Cockpit, Controller and Agents. Health check results can be forwarded, for example by mail.

<ul>
<li>Users can use health status results for integration with their monitoring system.</li>
<li>SOS offers a 24/7 Monitoring Service to receive health status results of customers using a commercial license who subscribe to this support option, see JS7 - License.</li>
</ul>

The JITL MonitoringJob template can be used as a building block in a monitoring solution to

<ul>
<li>repeatedly running the MonitoringJob template using a JS7 - Cycle Instruction,</li>
<li>forwarding health check results to a monitoring solution.</li>
<ul>
this can include to forward health check report files when used with a user's monitoring solution.
this can include to send e-mail indicating a notice or an alert to SOS. Such notices do not include any data related to the user's JS7 environment, they indicate a notice or alert only
</ul>
</ul>

The job template makes use of the JS7 - REST Web Service API to retrieve information from the JOC Cockpit.

<ul>
<li>The job template authenticates with the JS7 - REST Web Service API by use of user account/password and/or by use of a certificate, for details see JS7 - Authentication.</li>
</ul>
</p>
            
            
            
        </note>
    
        
         
    </documentation>

</description>
