<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="js7_job_documentation_v1.1.xsl"?>
<description xmlns="http://www.sos-berlin.com/schema/js7_job_documentation_v1.1"
             xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
             xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.sos-berlin.com/schema/js7_job_documentation_v1.1 http://www.sos-berlin.com/schema/js7_job_documentation_v1.1.xsd">
   <job xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
        name="OrderStateTransitionJob"
        title="Transition order states"
        category="Orders;JITL">
        <script language="java"
              java_class="com.sos.jitl.jobs.orderstatustransition.OrderStateTransitionJob"
              resource="1"/>
    </job>
   <configuration>
      <params id="job_parameter">
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="controller_id"
                required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>The identifier of a Controller can be specified to limit the resulting list of orders to the indicated Controller</title>
                    <p>Default: Current Controller ID</p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="states"
                required="true">
                <note>
                    <title>The state of orders that should be transitioned</title>
                    <p>Possible values: pending, failed, suspended, waiting, inprogress, scheduled, prompting. Values can be specified in uppercase, lowercase or mixed letters. 
                       Values can be specified from a semicolon separated list. Each state in the list is handled separately, for example
                        <ul>
                            <li>the transition continue for prompting orders will move orders to the IN PROGRESS and possibly to the RUNNING state,</li>
                            <li>the same transition for suspended orders will put orders to the state they had before being suspended.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="transition"
                required="true">
                <note>
                    <title>The transition operation for the order</title>
                    <p>Possible values are one of:
                        <ul>
                            <li>cancel: execute cancel operation on related orders</li>
                            <li>continue: execute resume operation on failed and suspended orders. Execute confirm operation on prompting orders.</li>
                            <li>suspend: execute suspend operation on orders that are not failed, not finished and not suspended.</li> 
                        </ul>
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="workflow_folders"
                required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>A list of folders that hold workflows for which orders should be transitioned</title>
                    <p>If more than one folder is specified then folders are separated by semicolon. When used with the trailing characters /* then the folder will be looked up recursively. By default all folders will be looked up recursively.</p>
                    <p>Examples: *myWorkflow*;my?orkflow</p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="workflow_search_patterns"
                required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>A list of search patterns for workflow folders that contains the orders</title>
                    <p>If more than one search pattern is used then they are separated by semicolon.</p>
                    <p>Examples: *myWorkflow*;/folder/sub1/my?orkflow</p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="order_search_patterns"
                required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>A list of search patterns for order names</title>
                    <p>If more than one search pattern is used then they are separated by semicolon.</p>
                    <p>Examples: *myWorkflow*;/folder/sub1/my?orkflow</p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="batch_size"
                required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>The maximum number of orders for a single request.</title>
                    <p>Default: 10000
                        <p>The maximum number of orders that are processed in a single request.</p>
                        <p>Orders are transitioned in a single transaction. This includes that either all orders in a transaction are transitioned or none. If the number of orders exceeds the batch size then a further transaction is executed.</p>
                        <p>If the value 1 is used for the batch_size then each order is transitioned individually with a successful or failed result.</p>
                        <p>The batch size should not exceed a value of approx. 15000 in order to limit the size of requests to the Controller to approx. 4 MB which is a frequently applied limit of Proxy Servers that might be in place between the Agent running the job and JOC Cockpit.                       </p>
                    </p>
                </note>
            </param>
            <param xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                name="persist_duration"
                required="false">
                <note>
                    <title>The duration the order persists in the failed state.</title>
                    <p>
Available for FAILED orders.
Example: 2d                     

a format for a period relative to the current time, e.g. 6h, 12h, 1d, 1w that specifies the quantity followed by a qualifier:
s (seconds)
m (minutes)
h (hours)
d (days)
w (weeks)
M (months)
y (years)
a time offset is optional (e.g. 2d+02:00)
it can also be specified with the parameter timeZone
if timeZone is undefined then UTC is used
the value 0 indicates the current time
</p>
                </note>
            </param>
      </params>
   </configuration>
   <documentation xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <note>
            <title>What is the purpose of this job?</title>
            <p>The JITL OrderStateTransitionJob template can be used to perform state transitions on orders. Examples for state transitions include to</p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>continue orders from the FAILED state to the IN PROGRESS state and possibly to the RUNNING state in case of a JS7 - Job Instruction,</li>
                    <li>continue orders from the SUSPENDED state to the state they had before being suspended.</li>
                    <li>continue orders from the PROMPTING state to the IN PROGRESS state and possibly to the RUNNING state.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>The job template makes use of the JS7 REST Web Service API to perform transitions, see "JS7 - Order State Transitions" article.</p>
            <p>The job template authenticates with the JS7 - REST Web Service API by use of user account/password and/or by use of a certificate, for details see "JS7 - Authentication" article.
               For details about configuration items see "JS7 - JITL Common Authentication" article.</p>
        </note>
    </documentation>
</description>